(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
重大告知
...わため呼び出し?!
Major Announcement
...Watame called out?!
みんなー！
Everyone!
こんばんドドドー！
Konban-dododo!
ホロライブ4期生、角巻わためです！
Hololive 4th generation, Tsunomaki Watame here!
今日はね、サムネにもあるんだけどね、
Today, as you can see in the thumbnail,
重大告知がね、あるみたいで。
there seems to be a major announcement.
わため、
Watame,
わかんない、なんだろうね？
doesn't know. I wonder what it is?
でもね、わかんないんだけどね、その代わりに、
But even though I don't know, instead,
なぜか今日は色んな方から呼び出しをね、受けててさ。
for some reason, I've been getting called out by various people today.
しかも誰が来るか、しらー知らないんだよね！
And I don't— I don't even know who's coming!
重大告知と関係あるのかね？どうなんだろうね？
I wonder if it's related to the major announcement? Who knows?
あ、今日はこんな感じで、まったり、のんびりやっていきますよ。
Ah, today we'll be taking it easy and relaxing like this.
たまにはね、3Dでのんびり配信しても悪くないよに～。
Sometimes, it's not bad to have a relaxing stream in 3D~.
ちょっとね、まだね、呼び出しの待ち合わせ時間までね、
Wait, there's still some time before,
時間があるっぽいから、お話ししますかね、みんなと。お話ししますかね？
the meeting time I was called for, so shall we chat, everyone? Shall we chat?
みんな見えてる？見えてる？
Can everyone see me? Can you see me?
すごいね、コメントの速度すげー！みんな「ねー」って言って。
Wow, the comment speed is amazing! Everyone's saying "yeah."
え、なんだと思う？今日の発表、みんななんだと思う？
Eh, what do you think? What do you think today's announcement is?
わためわかんないんだけどさ。
Watame doesn't know though.
もう何がもう1ミリもわかんないんだけどさ。なんだと思う？
I don't have a single clue. What do you think?
今までの角巻わため史上最大で、
The biggest in Tsunomaki Watame's history,
えー、なんだっけ、最高で最強な？重大告知って言ってたっけ？
uh, what was it, the best and strongest? Did they call it a major announcement?
告白とか？ジンギスカンパーティー？
A confession? A Genghis Khan party?
え？最後の晩餐なの？今日。あれおかしいな。
Eh? Is this the last supper? Today. That's strange.
恐いの。もっといいお話しだったと思うんだけどね。
It's scary. I thought it was going to be better news.
あ、わかんないけどね。何のことかわからんけどね。
Well, I don't know. I have no idea what it's about.
わためや...
Watame...
は！
Ha!
わためや...
Watame...
誰だ？
Who's there?
ボタンちゃん... 獅白ぼたんじゃよ。
It's Botan-chan... Shishiro Botan.
ボタンちゃん？ え？なんか仙人みたいになってる。
Botan-chan? Eh? You look like some kind of hermit.
え？神様になったの？
Eh? Did you become a god?
獅白ぼたんです。
I'm Shishiro Botan.
おら、ようこそ。
Hey, welcome.
今日は私を呼び出してどうするつもりだ？
What do you plan to do with me after calling me out today?
パーティーか？ジンギスカンパーティーなのか？
A party? Is it a Genghis Khan party?
出荷でもしようかな。
Maybe I'll ship you off.
ひいいい！おかしいよ！
Hieeee! That's not right!
待て待て待て、こんなおどろおどろしい登場しましたけれども、まあ今日は特に何もないですよ。
Wait wait wait, you made such a creepy entrance, but there's nothing special going on today.
ほんま？
Really?
ほんまほんま。ただね、ちょっとね、わためとちょっとゆっくりお話ししたいなと思って、
Really, really. I just wanted to have a relaxed chat with Watame,
今日はちょっとここね、わための隠れ家に遊びに来たわけですよ。
so I came to visit Watame's hideout here today.
あ、そうね、この場所バレちゃったからね。
Ah, that's right, since this place was discovered.
そう、バレちゃったからね。もう、もう道覚えちゃったからね。もう逃げれねーからな。
Yeah, since it was discovered. I've already memorized the way. There's no escaping now.
怖！でも今日は何もないんだもんね？
Scary! But there's nothing today, right?
うん、何もない、何もない。
Yeah, nothing, nothing.
そう、何もない。だから今日は本当にもう...
Right, nothing. So today is really just...
え、何？ え？ ゆっくり... お？ 何？ え？ すごい何？ 何？
Eh, what? Eh? Relaxing... Oh? What? Eh? What is that? What?
ゆっくり... 何か投げた？
Relaxing... Did you throw something?
あ、気にしないで。今日の天気... あの、今日の天気あの、晴れ時々手榴弾だから。
Ah, don't worry about it. The weather today... um, today's weather is sunny with occasional grenades.
晴れ時々手榴ー え？ お？ なんか、え？ え？
Sunny with occasional gren- Eh? Oh? Something's... eh? Eh?
気にしないで。
Don't worry about it.
え？雨だけじゃなくて手榴弾降るなんて聞いたの？
Eh? I never heard about grenades falling instead of rain.
まあそんな日もあると思う。
Well, I guess there are days like that.
あるかな？ まあ最近ちょっと異常気象だしね。
I wonder? Well, the weather has been a bit extreme lately.
そうそう。
True, true.
あると思うんだ。
I think there is.
なるほどね。
I see.
もう気にしないでいいってことかな？
Does that mean I don't have to worry about it anymore?
当たんねえな。
It's not hitting.
ほう、何て？タイマー？
What? What did you say? Timer?
あ、ごめん。何でもない。
Ah, sorry. It's nothing.
当たんねえって言った？
Did you say it's not hitting?
あ、何でもない、何でもない。
Ah, it's nothing, it's nothing.
今かすった！かすった！かすったよ今！
It grazed me just now! It grazed! It grazed me just now!
かすったか。惜しいな。
It grazed you? Too bad.
いっつー、これお風呂しみるやつだ。
Ouch, this is the kind that stings in the bath.
ふー。
Phew.
でもぼたんちゃんが手榴弾投げてくるんだったら...
But if Botan-chan is going to throw grenades...
わためだって負けないんだぜ！
...Watame won't lose either!
おー？
Oh?
まあ見てな。見てな。わための反撃... ほら！
Just watch. Just watch. Watame's counterattack... Here!
おー、結構似合ってる。
Oh, it suits you quite well.
片手で撃ってやがる。
She's firing it with one hand.
ははは！反動もねえぜ！
Hahaha! There's no recoil!
本当だ、反動もねえ。何てことだ。
It's true, there's no recoil. Good grief.
じゃあ、まあ、そんなんでね。じゃあどうしようかな。今から、じゃあ３分間くらいちょっと雑談して...
So, well, with that. Now, what should we do. From now, let's chat for about 3 minutes...
...終わった頃にわためが無事だったら...
...and if Watame is safe by the time we're done...
...今日重大告知あるらしいじゃない。それにに関する...
...I heard there's a major announcement today. Related to that...
秘密のキーワードを、わたくしが教えてあげます、一つ。
I will tell you one secret keyword.
何？キーワード？
What? Keyword?
キーワードです。
A keyword.
オッケー。
Okay.
はい。じゃあ何話しましょう。何か、何か飲んでくつろげるようなトークテーマがいいかなと思うんですけど。
Yes. So what shall we talk about. I think a talk theme that's relaxing, like having a drink, would be good.
これ重いんだ、あ、重いんだね、これって！
This is heavy! Ah, this is heavy!
めっちゃ軽々しく片手で上げてたけど。
You were raising it with one hand so easily, though.
無事にトークをしよう！
Let's chat peacefully!
いや、まあさっきも言った通り、まあトークをしつつ３分間生き残ったらってことなので。
Well, as I said before, it's about surviving for 3 minutes while chatting.
おめ... え、命かかってんの？
Wait... Is my life on the line?
トークしつつ... そうだね、トークしつつちょっと避けてください。
While chatting... yes, please dodge while chatting.
わかりました。
Understood.
はい。で、わため夏休みに何... 何かやってます？
Yes. So, Watame, are you doing... anything for summer vacation?
休みなんてねえ！
There's no such thing as a vacation!
あ、結構忙しいんだね。
Ah, you're quite busy.
休みある？何か休んだ？
Is there a vacation? Did I rest?
うー、特になんか休んだ記憶ねえな。
Hmm, I don't really have any memory of resting.
ねえな！あの、ほら、ちょっとわたくし１周年だったので。
None! You see, it was my 1st anniversary.
あ、そうだね。
Ah, that's right.
確か。そうそう、わためもね、ありがとね、出てくれてね。
Exactly. That's right, and thank you, Watame, for appearing.
いや、呼んでくれてありがとね。おれ、でも誕生日とか、あれ？
No, thank you for inviting me. But wait, birthday or something...?
近くなかったっけ？あぶね、今忙しいんだけどね。
Wasn't it close? Careful, I'm busy right now though.
まだちょっと忙しいんだけどね。まあまあまあ。
I'm still a bit busy though. Well, well.
でもね、わためさんのね、お誕生日もね、わたくし呼んでいただけて嬉しかったです。
But I was happy to be invited to Watame-san's birthday too.
また、呼ぶよ。
I'll invite you again.
ありがとね。何か遊んでよ。
Thank you. Let's hang out.
暇だったら遊んで。
Hang out when you're free.
またやろうね。
Let's do it again.
これ、振らせ、これ振らせれるのかな？もっと振らせれるのかな？
Can I swing this? Can I swing this more?
もっと振らせれるのかな？過激派だな。
Can you swing it more? You're a radical.
あべ！余裕だね。
Abe! It's easy.
いや、ここのね、わためのね、実家が広いからね。
No, it's because Watame's family home is wide here.
ちょっと避けやすいよね。あべ！
It's a bit easy to dodge. Abe!
あぶな。何かね、今コメントで「今当たったよ」ってコメントありますけど。当たりました？
Watch out. Someone in the comments just said "It hit just now". Did it hit?
当たってないよな！当たってないよな！
It didn't hit! It didn't hit!
当たった、当たったって言われてるけど。当たってないよな。
They're saying it hit, it hit. But you say it didn't.
当たってないよな。かすり傷？でも大丈夫だ。
It didn't hit. Just a scratch? But I'm fine.
あ、何か痛くなってきたかもしれない。
Ah, it might be starting to hurt.
あれ？
Oh?
でも、生き延びればいいのだろ。なる、終わっちゃ...
But as long as I survive, it's fine. Right? It's ending...
ま、１０分も経ってないのに！終わっちゃよ！
It's not even been 10 minutes yet! It's ending!
生き延びればいいんでしょ。怪我しててもね。
I just have to survive, right? Even if I'm injured.
あ、あ、上手いんだろう。
Ah, I'm good at this.
あ、何のゴングでしょう。
Ah, what was that gong?
何のゴング？
What gong?
お時間です。無事、はい、無事生き残りました。おめでとうございます。
Time's up. You safely, yes, you safely survived. Congratulations.
コングラチュレーション。
Congratulations.
いや、コングラチュレーション！いぇーい！
No, congratulations! Yay!
ダダダ、出ない。ダダダダダダダ！いぇーい！
Dadada, it's not coming out. Dadadadadadada! Yay!
まあね、わためが無事でよかったよ。
Well, I'm glad you're safe, Watame.
いや、あぶな。何か当たったんじゃないかって言われたけど。
No, that was close. I was told that maybe I got hit.
まあ大丈夫、生きてるから大丈夫。楽しかった。これちゃんと話できたかな。
Well, it's okay, you're alive so it's fine. It was fun. Did we manage to talk properly?
じゃあね、わために約束通り重大告知に関する秘密のキーワードね、教えちゃう。
So, as promised, I'll tell Watame the secret keyword for the major announcement.
何、何？
What is it?
いい？じゃあリスナーの皆さんもね、キーワード一つ教えます。
Ready? So, listeners, I'll tell you one keyword too.
キーワードは、数字の６です。
The keyword is the number 6.
６？
6?
６です。
It's 6.
６？何だ？
6? What is it?
わかんないな。
I don't get it.
まあね、時期わかると思うので。まあこれからもちょっとキーワード集めてよ。
Well, you'll understand in time. So, keep collecting keywords from now on.
分かった。頑張るわ。
Understood. I'll do my best.
ありがとう！ぼたん神様ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you, Goddess Botan!
それじゃあわしはこの辺で。またな。
Well then, I'll be off now. See ya.
またな！
See ya!
またな！あぶ･･･あぶないあぶない。
See ya! Whoa... careful, careful.
あぶね、あぶね。
That was close.
なんだろうね？ぼたんちゃんありがとう。
I wonder what it is? Thanks, Botan-chan.
『６』ってなんだろうね？
I wonder what '6' is for?
とりあえずこの装備外しておこうかな。物騒だからね。
Anyway, let's take this equipment off. It's dangerous.
みんな分かる？なんだろうね？
Do you guys know? I wonder what it is.
え、まさか６期生？
Eh, could it be the 6th generation?
いや、わためがそんな重大な･･･
No, for Watame to have such a major...
あ、なんだ？角で何か動画を受信したぞ！ビビビビビビ･･･
Oh, what's this? I've received a video through my horns! Beep beep beep...
なんだ？
What is it?
わため先輩、こんばんドドド！Hololive English Myth's Calliope Mori here.
Watame-senpai, konban-do-do-do! Hololive English Myth's Calliope Mori here.
先輩、元気ですか？
Senpai, how are you?
うわ！
Whoa!
今は私ね、旅行中ですが、今夜わため先輩にお会いしたいと思いました。
I'm traveling right now, but I wanted to see you tonight, Watame-senpai.
わため先輩の歌声、すごく素敵だよ。
Watame-senpai, your singing voice is wonderful.
最高の音楽、ありがとうございます。いつも聴いていますよ。
Thank you for the great music. I'm always listening.
よかったらぜひまたコラボしたいよね。
I'd love to collab with you again if you're up for it.
その時まで、私ね、わため先輩の活動をよく見るつもりです。
Until then, I'm planning to keep a close eye on your activities, Watame-senpai.
よろしくね。
Looking forward to it.
かわいい！
So cute!
私からのチャレンジをクリアできたら、キーワードを教えてあげます。
If you can clear my challenge, I'll give you a keyword.
チャレンジは、今から１分間英語で自己紹介と趣味と
The challenge is, for one minute starting now, introduce yourself and your hobbies in English,
自分の好きなことを語ってください。
and talk about the things you like.
日本語を使ったら、アウトですよ。
If you use Japanese, you're out.
それでは、わため先輩、頑張ってください！
Well then, Watame-senpai, good luck!
Bye bye!
えええー！
Eeeeh?!
カリオピちゃんありがとう！ありがとうだけど･･･
Kalliopi-chan, thank you! Thank you, but...
英語で何か言ってって言ってたね。やってみようか。
She said to say something in English. Shall I try?
もうチャレンジしてみようかな。
I guess I'll take on the challenge.
あ、そうや。でもねわためもちょっとラッパーぽい･･･
Ah, that's right. But you know, Watame is also a bit of a rapper...
イヨ、イヨ！
Yo, yo!
イヨ、サングラス持ってるからこれつけてもいい？いい？コスプレ、コスプレしてもいい？
Yo, I have sunglasses, so can I wear them? Is it okay? Can I do a cosplay?
ちょっとつけるわ。
I'll put them on.
ちょっとね、あの、カマなかったから斧でもいいかな？あはは。
Well, since I didn't have a scythe, maybe an axe is okay? Haha.
カマなかったから、ちょ斧で頑張る。
Since I didn't have a scythe, I'll do my best with this axe.
ちょっとカリオピちゃんをイメージして頑張ります。
I'll do my best by channeling my inner Kalliopi-chan.
では･･･
Well then...
チャレンジスタート！
Challenge start!
My name is Watame Tsunomaki.
And... uh... uh... My...
My hobby is... My hobby is...
Uh, share happy. Share happy equal food, food!
Uh, share happy. Share happy equals food, food!
Food meshitero, yeah!
Meshitero, yeah!
I like sing a song.
I like sing a song... and funny dance.
Funny dance.
Funny dance... and...
I like apple. I like pineapple.
I like Pen-Pineapple-Apple-Pen! Yeah!
I like... I like... game.
I like... I like... games.
And stream, yeah!
And streaming, yeah!
Good morning mada stream, yeah!
Thank you!
はい、パーペク！はい、完ペク！
Yes, perfect! Yes, flawless!
これクリアだよね？ね？
I cleared it, right? Right?
Hello, hello again! Wow! Nice job, senpai! 英語上手！
Hello, hello again! Wow! Nice job, senpai! You're good at English!
Your English is really great. You are amazing.
I want to teach you English someday.
Please help me with my Japanese.
それでは、キーワードのプレゼントです。
Now then, here is your keyword gift.
キーワードは『Ｉ』です。
The keyword is 'I'.
先輩またね！頑張って！
Senpai, see you later! Good luck!
Bye bye!
英語の『Ｉ』！
The English 'I'!
数字の次は英語か。謎だな。
After a number, it's an English letter. It's a mystery.
わからない。６と『Ｉ』、なんだろうね？
I don't know. '6' and 'I', I wonder what they mean?
カリオピちゃんありがとうね！なんか今回ね、角で受信できるようになりました。
Thank you, Kalliopi-chan! Somehow, I can receive transmissions through my horns now.
斧の装備もね、
Put on the axe equipment...
身につけました。イエーイ！
I've put it on. Yay!
ああ、この斧めっちゃ重かったな。
Ah, this axe was really heavy.
よいしょっと。
Heave-ho.
重かったな、めっちゃ。
It was really heavy.
さてと。
Well then.
これね、あとね3組ぐらいにね、ちょっと呼び出されてんだけどね。
You know, I've been summoned by about three more groups.
まったくわため、おらは人気もんだな！
Geez, Watame, I'm a popular person!
ガハハハハ！
Gahahaha!
わわわわわわわ！わため〜！
Wa-wa-wa-wa-wa! Watame~!
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
アーニャ？アーニャ！？
Anya? Anya!?
おねえさ〜ん。
Onee-san~
インドネシア1期生、アーニャ・メルフィッサでーす。
I'm Anya Melfissa from ID 1st gen!
わたさ〜ん！
Wata-san!
もしもし〜。
Hello~.
アーニャも告知を聞きに来てくれたの？
Did Anya come to hear the announcement too?
そうなの？
Is that so?
もちろん！
Of course!
そう、もちろんタダでは教えませんよ。
Yes, but of course, I won't tell you for free.
え、教えてよ〜。
Eh, tell me~.
教えなーいです。
I won't tell you.
教えなーい。
I won't tell.
私から、私からのチャレンジは絵のお題です。
My challenge, my challenge is a drawing topic.
絵のお題？
A drawing topic?
そう、お絵かきですよ。
Yes, it's drawing.
なるほど。
I see.
じゃあちょっとね、わため画伯に変身するから待ってて。
Then wait a moment while I transform into 'Painter Watame'.
お、了解です。
Oh, roger that.
へ〜んしん！
Trans-form!
チェンジ！
Change!
おー！
Oh!
似合ってます！
It suits you!
似合ってる？
It suits me?
イエーイ！
Yay!
絵描くぞ〜！
I'm going to draw!
イエーイ！
Yay!
よし、いきましょう！
Alright, let's go!
じゃあ、わためはこっち座るわ。
Then, Watame will sit here.
さて、チャレンジの内容なんですがね、アーニャがわため先輩にドローイングの指示を出します。
Now, for the challenge content, Anya will give drawing instructions to Watame-senpai.
で、アーニャの指示通りに描いていただければとある物になるので、自分の絵を見てお題の物を当てられればチャレンジクリアということで。
If you draw as instructed, it'll become something. If you guess it from your drawing, you clear the challenge.
なるほど。アーニャの指示通りに描けばいいんだね。
I see. I just have to draw according to Anya's instructions, right?
そうそう。説明だけだとちょっと分かりにくいと思いますので、これで一旦練習問題に行きましょうか。
Right. It's a bit hard to understand with just words, so let's try a practice question first.
オッケー。
Okay.
オッケー。準備はいいですか？
Okay. Are you ready?
オッケー、いつでも来い！
Okay, bring it on anytime!
じゃあ、まずは丸を描いてもらいます。
Then, first, please draw a circle.
丸？
A circle?
適当でいいの？
Is it okay if it's just rough?
お、適当で。もうホントに大きくても小さくても何でも大丈夫なんで。
Oh, just rough. Really, big or small, anything is fine.
お、丸描いてやる。
Oh, I'll draw a circle.
オッケー。
Okay.
オッケー。で、その丸の上にアホ毛をつけます。1本で大丈夫なんで。
Okay. And on top of that circle, add an 'ahoge'. One is fine.
アホ毛？
An ahoge?
イエ、アホ毛を1本で大丈夫なんで。
Yeah, just one ahoge is fine.
こういうこと？
Like this?
そうそうそう。アホ毛で。
Right, right, right. An ahoge.
えっ、1本しか描かないよ、これ。もうちょっと太い...
Eh, I'm only drawing one. A bit thicker...
太くしてもいいんですか？
Is it okay to make it thicker?
そうそうそう。もうちょっと、もうちょっとアホ毛をもうちょっと、何だろうね、ボサっと。
Right. A bit more... make the ahoge a bit more, what's the word, messy.
こう？
Like this?
お！
Oh!
こういうこと？
Like this?
そうそう。何これ？
Right. What is this?
えっ、そう、それで何だと思いますか？
Eh, yes, so what do you think it is?
えー？
Eh?
これ、何これ？
This, what is this?
何だと思いますか？
What do you think it is?
えっ、カブ？
Eh, a turnip?
えー、惜しいですね。味は甘いです。
Eh, close. The taste is sweet.
甘い？
Sweet?
さっき甘い。
Sweet earlier.
さっき好きな物の話だと言ってましたよ、さっき。
You were talking about things you like earlier.
あ、リンゴ！？
Ah, an apple!?
正解です！
Correct!
あ、リンゴだったのこれ。なるほど。
Ah, this was an apple. I see.
リンゴだったんだこれ。
So it was an apple.
なるほど。リンゴに近いです、これは。
I see. It's close to an apple.
リンゴだったんだ。
It was an apple.
おー、流石ですね。
Oh, as expected.
毛かと思った。
I thought it was hair.
あ、そう？
Ah, really?
1本毛かと。リンゴに感じますよ。
Thought it was a strand of hair. It feels like an apple.
オッケー。ということで、次は本番ですね。
Okay. So, next is the real thing.
本番ですね。
The real thing.
オッケー。本番ですよ。
Okay. It's the real thing.
いけますか？オッケー。
Are you ready? Okay.
じゃあ、いきますよ、スタート！
Then, here we go, start!
まずは雲を描いてみます。雲。もうホントにその雲ね、めっちゃモコモコにしてください。
First, try drawing a cloud. A cloud. Really, make that cloud very fluffy.
モコモコ？
Fluffy?
そう、モコモコな雲ですよ、雲。柔らかそうな。
Yes, a fluffy cloud, a cloud. Soft-looking.
こう？
Like this?
そう、で、真ん中に丸を2つです。
Yes, and then two circles in the middle.
真ん中に丸を2つ？
Two circles in the middle?
そう、丸を2つですよ。
Yes, two circles.
何これ、えー。
What is this, uh...
最後にな、左側と右側にちょっと渦巻きっぽいのを描いてみましょう。
Finally, let's draw something like swirls on the left and right sides.
どこどこどこ？その渦巻きどこ？
Where, where, where? Where are those swirls?
そうそう、あのもう何だろうね、モコモコのあたりにその左側と右側に渦巻きを描いてみましょう。
Right. Let's draw swirls on the left and right sides of the fluffy area.
こう？プルプルプルって、こ、こう？
Like this? Puru-puru-puru... l-like this?
あ、そうそう、上手です。もう、もうちょっと。そうそうそう。
Ah, right, you're good. Just a bit more. Right, right, right.
そう...
So...
もう一つ...
Another one...
あ、そこ、そこそこそこそこ！
Ah, there, there, there, there!
描けた！
I'm done!
そう、では何だと思いますか？
So, what do you think it is?
ひつじ！
A sheep!
あら？
Oh?
いぇーい！
Yay!
うぉぉー！すごーい！
Whoa! Amazing!
ひつじー！チャレンジクリアですよー！
Sheep! Challenge cleared!
やったー！
We did it!
おめでとうございますー！
Congratulations!
ひつじやったね！
It was a sheep!
うん。やってやってやってますね、心が。
Yeah. You're really doing it, with your heart.
ということでチャレンジクリア！
And so, challenge cleared!
キーワード、押しますか？
Shall we reveal the keyword?
お願いします！
Please!
では、キーワードは...
Okay, the keyword is...
そうです！ひらがなの「そ」！
That's right! The hiragana 'so'!
ひらがなの「そ」！
The hiragana 'so'!
そうです！ここにきてひらがな！
That's right! Hiragana at this stage!
なんだろう？
I wonder what it is.
何でしょうね。レオ、今日はありがとうございました！また遊びましょう！
I wonder. Leo, thank you so much for today! Let's play again!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
失礼しましたー！頑張ってくださいねー！
Excuse me! Good luck with everything!
またねー！
Bye-bye!
はい、スクショタイムですよー！
Okay, it's screenshot time!
えー、「そ」？なんだろうね、ここにきて「そ」かー。
Eh, 'so'? I wonder what it is. Hiragana 'so' at this point.
わかる？みんな。
Do you guys know?
6に、Iに、そ。わかんない。ま、でもね、わため画伯大活躍だったぜ！ガハハ！
6, I, and 'so'. I don't know. But anyway, Watame the artist did a great job! Gahaha!
完璧だったねー。
It was perfect.
みんな、今まで全部完璧だね。
Everyone, everything's been perfect so far.
んなー。いや、でも、今思ったけどみんなこれ、わため先輩ってね、後輩が来てくれて嬉しいねー。
Nnaa. I just thought about it, but it's great that my juniors come and call me 'Watame-senpai'.
わためとわかんないみんな、みんなわかんないって言ってるけどわためもわかんない。なんだろう。
You guys say you don't know, and Watame doesn't know either. I wonder what it is.
でも嬉しいね、先輩になったってもうさ、感慨深いな。
But it's nice, becoming a senior... it's deeply moving.
あといくつあるんだろうね。
I wonder how many more there are.
わためちゃん。
Watame-chan.
はっ！この声は...！
Ha! That voice is...!
どうも、ふーみです。
Hello, I'm Fumi.
ふーみママ！
Fumi-mama!
ママ、ついに！えっ！？もしかして重大告知って、ふーみママが初めて配信に出るってこと？
Mama, finally! Eh? Does this big announcement mean Fumi-mama is appearing on stream for the first time?
だったの？違うの？
Is that it? Or am I wrong?
重大告知はわためちゃんのことだよ。
The big announcement is about you, Watame-chan.
えっ、そうなの？ふーみママのことじゃないの？
Eh, is that so? It's not about Fumi-mama?
そう。なんかすごい重大な任務が書かれてたので来たんだけど、何したんだろう。
Yeah, I saw some big mission was written, so I came, but I wonder what you did.
そうなんだー。じゃあ、お話しすればいいのかな？
I see! Should we talk a bit?
なんか、配信したことない初心者が、こんなすごい配信に来ちゃって大丈夫かなーって。
I was wondering if it's okay for a beginner who has never streamed before to be on such a big stream.
大丈夫ですよ、みんな！いやー、出てきてくれた。えっ、ちょっと色々質問してもいい？
It's fine, everyone! Yay, she came! Can I ask you a few questions?
はい。
Sure.
ママに。じゃあ、何、絵を描くきっかけは、何だったの？
For Mama. What was the reason you started drawing?
小さい頃から落書きはしてたんだけど。
I've been doodling since I was little.
その延長線上かな。
It's an extension of that, I guess.
へー！何歳ぐらいから？
I see! Since when exactly?
幼稚園とか。
Since kindergarten or so.
あら！5歳とか？
Around 5 years old?
そう。
Yeah.
あ、じゃあわためもこれいけるんじゃないかなー。いや、こんな軽々しく言っちゃダメね。
Ah! Then maybe Watame can do it too? Well, I shouldn't say that so lightly.
頑張ろう、でも。えっ、もっと聞いてもいい？
I'll do my best though. Eh, can I ask more?
はい。
Sure.
いやー一個気になることがあってさ。今までのグッズとかでさ。
There's one thing I'm curious about. About the previous merchandise...
わためなんか「穿いてない説」が出てるんだけどさ。穿いてないのかな？みんな気になってると思う。
There's a theory that Watame isn't wearing anything... are you not wearing anything? Everyone's curious.
穿いてるときと、穿いてないときが。
There are times when I'm wearing them... and times when I'm not.
はっ！？穿いてないときあった！？
What!? There were times when you weren't!?
みんな新情報！穿いてないときあるぞ、これ！
New info, everyone! There are times when she's not wearing them!
どれがどれかはご想像にお任せしよう。
I'll leave it to your imagination which is which.
あとはね、何、今おパンツ様穿いてる？ふーみママは。
Also... are you wearing panties right now, Fumi-mama?
穿いてるよ。
I am.
何色？
What color?
えっ、そこもじゃあ、ご想像にお任せということで。
Eh? Well, I'll leave that to your imagination too.
えー！じらしてるー！ママのパンツの色、今度見とこ。
Aww, teasing us! I'll check Mama's panties later.
今度見とこ。なんか逆に聞きたいこととかある？
I'll check them later. Is there anything you want to ask me?
えーっと、この重大発表のために、わためちゃんがすごい頑張って活動してる。
Well... for this big announcement... Watame-chan, you've been working so hard.
してて、配信外でも忙しいと思うけど、配信時間もすごいから。
I think you're busy even off-stream, and your stream time is also long.
体調が心配。
I'm worried about your health.
えっ！全然大丈夫だよ！元気！勇気！つのまき！
Oh! I'm totally fine! Energetic! Courageous! Tsunomaki!
え、ふーみママも今、忙しいと思うんですけど...
Uh, I think Fuumi-mother is also busy right now...
大丈夫？大丈夫？
Are you okay? Are you okay?
あ、元気だよ。
Ah, I'm fine.
元気。え、いつ寝てんの？ふーみママ。
You're fine. Uh, when do you sleep, Fuumi-mother?
気になる。
I'm curious.
なんか、うん、色んな時間に寝てる。
Like, yeah, I sleep at various times.
色んな時間？
Various times?
大体配信見てくれてるよね？なんか。
You're usually watching my streams, right?
なんか寝る時に寝てるかな。
I guess I sleep when it's time to sleep.
寝る時に寝てる？
You sleep when you sleep?
ちゃんと寝てます。
I'm sleeping properly.
何時間？
For how many hours?
日による？ ７時間とかかな。
Depends on the day? Maybe 7 hours or so.
あ、結構寝てるね！
Oh, you sleep quite a bit!
わためも結構それぐらい寝てる。
Watame also sleeps about that much.
それならよかった。
That's good then.
大丈夫だぜ！
It's all good!
ご飯何が好き？
What kind of food do you like?
ご飯はね、イタリアンとか。
Food-wise, I like Italian and stuff.
へー！今度一緒に行ってくれる？
Oh! Will you go with me next time?
あ、行きたい！
Ah, I'd love to!
行きたい！
You want to go!
え、じゃあもう一個聞きたいのがある。
Oh, then there's one more thing I want to ask.
今後わためとお絵かきコラボ配信とかする
What is the probability of a future
可能性は何パーセントですか！？
drawing collab stream with Watame!?
これ、うわー、どうしようかな...
This, wow, what should I do...
なんか、いや、喋るのが苦手...
Well, you see, I'm not good at talking...
そうだよね、いや今日も...
Right, well today too...
ちょっとハードル高すぎ。どうしよう。
The hurdle is a bit too high. What to do?
今日もね、出てくれるとは思わなかったよ。だめもとで頼んだ。
I didn't think you'd appear today either. I just asked anyway.
断れないような...
It felt like I couldn't refuse...
呼び出されてんの。あ、そうだ。
You were summoned. Ah, that's right.
あ、そうなんだ！
Oh, I see!
断れなかったかー。
So you couldn't say no.
圧に負けたか。
Did you give in to the pressure?
いや、やっぱりね、発表会だからね。うん。
No, after all, it's an announcement event. Yeah.
えー！やりたーい！また一緒に。
Eh! I want to do it! Together again.
じゃあ後で相談しましょう。
Then let's discuss it later.
やったー！来たー！みんな聞いたか！？言質取りましたよ！
Yay! It's here! Everyone, did you hear that!? I got her word!
イェーイ！
Yay!
楽しみだな。
I'm looking forward to it.
いや、絵を教えてほしいんだよ。
No, I want you to teach me how to draw.
何使ってる？うん。
What do you use?
え、普通にお絵かきソフト...
Uh, just normal drawing software...
何何？
Which one?
フォトショップ。
Photoshop.
あー！使ったことないんだよなー。
Ah! I've never used that before.
私、クリスタしか使ったことないから、
I've only used Clip Studio, so
教えてほしい、逆に。
I want you to teach me, conversely.
え、教えっこする？
Eh, shall we teach each other?
え、でも教えることないよ！そんな使いこなせないぜ。
But I have nothing to teach! I can't use it that well.
でもせっかく液タブ買ったから、
But since I have a liquid tab...
買ったっていうか、買ってもらったんだけどさ。
well, more like I had it bought for me.
ドラゴンね。
XP-Pen, right.
液タブ使えないんだよね。上手く書けない。
I can't really use the liquid tab. I can't draw well.
どうしたらいいと思う？
What do you think I should do?
練習やっぱり...
Practice, after all...
あれ？ふーみママの霊圧が消えた！
Huh? Fuumi-mother's presence disappeared!
ふーみママ！
Fuumi-mother!
ふーみママ！！
Fuumi-mother!!
霊圧が消えた！
Her presence is gone!
わあ！わためが！
Waa! Watame...!
パンチの色なんて聞いたから！
It's because I asked about the color of her panties!
そういうことだ！
That's why!
履いてるか、履いてないか聞いたから！
Because I asked if she was wearing them or not!
バンされちゃったってこと！？
Does that mean she got banned!?
ふーみママがー！うー！
Fuumi-mother is...! Uuu!
なんて罪なことを！初めてなのに！
What a sinful thing I've done! And it was our first time!
申し訳ねえぜ！
I'm so sorry!
ないなった。ふーみママないなった。
She's gone. Fuumi-mother is gone.
でもコメント、めっちゃ草生えてる。
But the comments are full of 'grass' (lol).
みんなもないなっとる。
Everyone is also saying she's gone.
でも今度コラボしたいね。
But I want to collab next time.
絵、描いてほしいよな。
I want her to draw for me.
ね、みんなもさ、いつも配信とかでさ、
Right, everyone, always in streams and stuff...
ふーみママとコラボねーの？なーの？って言ってたからさ。
you guys were asking if there was a collab with Fuumi-mother.
やっと今回、お喋りしてるとこ見せられるって思ったんだけど...
I thought I could finally show us chatting this time, but...
ふーみママ連れ去られちゃった。
Fuumi-mother was taken away.
連れ去られちゃった。
She was taken away.
さらわれちゃった。
She was snatched away.
あれ、そういえばキーワードももらってない、キーワードないなった！
Oh, come to think of it, I haven't gotten the keyword. It's gone!
キーワードないなったということは
If the keyword is gone, that means
今日の重大告知も...ないなった！
today's major announcement is also... gone!
うー！
Uuu!
悲しいぜ！うー！
It's so sad! Uuu!
でも、他にもね、まだ呼び出されてんだよね。
But, there are others who have been summoned as well.
もう...次の人に。
Already... moving to the next person.
ん？
Hmm?
お時間とかなのかな〜
I wonder if it's time yet...
いい加減かな〜
I wonder if they're coming...
まだかな〜
Not yet?
Still not here...
来ないね
They're not coming, are they?
じゃあちょっと話しながら待ってますかね
Well, I'll just talk a bit while I wait.
ね、まあこれも生配信のいいところですよね
Yeah, this is the good thing about live streaming, isn't it?
な
Right?
あ、メンバーシップいらっしゃい
Oh, welcome to the membership!
はっはっはっは！
Hahahaha!
わため！
Watame!
この声は！
This voice is...!
ちょっとフーミママ、変なことやらないで、びっくりするから
Wait, Fuumi-mama, don't do anything weird! You'll surprise me.
え、もしかして、バカタレ城に連れ去られたってことか！？
Wait, could it be you were kidnapped to the Bakatare Castle!?
そうだよ
That's right!
フーミママは今、バカタレ城の中に囚われの身だ
Fuumi-mama is now a prisoner inside the Bakatare Castle.
いつの間にバカタレ城なんて建ってたんだ！？
When did a Bakatare Castle get built!?
一夜で建ってたのか？
Was it built overnight?
フブちゃんならバカタレ共和国にはちゃんと城があるんだ！
For Fubuchan, the Bakatare Republic has a proper castle!
知らなかったんだけど！
I didn't know that!
フブちゃんならなんでもやるぞ！
Fubuchan can do anything!
バカタレ凄すぎる...
The Bakatare are way too amazing...
待て、お、立てるぞ一晩で城なんて！
Wait, she can build a castle in a single night!
一晩で、フブちゃんがやってくれました
Fubuchan did it in just one night.
そうだ！
That's right!
わーい！
Yay!
やりました！
We did it!
返してくれよ、フーミママ！
Give us back Fuumi-mama!
どうしよっかな〜
I wonder what we should do~
ちょっとフーミママより先にまず、私たちとやることがあるんじゃないか？
Wait, before Fuumi-mama, don't you have something to do with us first?
あ、確かにそうですね！
Ah, that's true!
フーミママの前にですね、
Before Fuumi-mama,
わためにキーワードを伝えればならぬという使命があるんだった
we have a mission to tell Watame the keyword.
なに？
What?
そう、でもね、やっぱただでは教えないぞと
Right, but we won't just give it to you for free.
私たちからのお題をクリアできたら、キーワード教えてあげるよ
If you can clear our challenge, we'll tell you the keyword.
えー！
Eh!
そう来なくっちゃ。お題は何だい？
Now we're talking. What's the challenge?
ほいほいほい、お題はですね、
Alright then, the challenge is...
我々とトークしている時にバレずに海苔を食べよう！だ！
to eat seaweed without us noticing while we're talking!
バレずに海苔を食べよう！
Eat seaweed without getting caught!
くだらねぇ〜！(笑)
That's so silly! (Laughs)
まあまあまあ、楽勝だ
Well, well, well. This will be a piece of cake.
本当か？
Are you sure?
簡単ですよ。ルールな、ルールは簡単だぞ
It's easy. Here are the rules... the rules are simple.
ほら、たくさんいて、あの3枚のね、海苔を用意してもらいました
Look, we've had three pieces of seaweed prepared for you.
で、そのうちの1枚でも、私たちにバレずに食べたら、わための勝ち
If you eat even one of them without us noticing, Watame wins.
なるほど
I see.
もし、食べてる時に、私たちに指摘されたら、その海苔は無効で、そのまま美味しく食べていただきます
If we catch you eating, that piece won't count, but you can go ahead and enjoy it.
はい
Okay.
で、トーク終了になったら、1枚でも食べれたか聞くので、そこでジャッジするからね
When we finish talking, I'll ask if you managed to eat at least one, and I'll judge then.
はい
Understood.
わかった。用意はいいですか？
Got it. Are you guys ready?
あ、やってやんぜ！
Oh, let's do this!
あ、でも、ちょっと気合い入れるために、いつものカブトを締めさせていただきます！
Wait, to get myself pumped up, let me put on my usual helmet!
失礼いたします。ギュッ！
Pardon me. *Tightens*
定番になっちゃったよ
It's become a tradition.
将軍が...
The Shogun...
あ、来た！わため将軍！ははー！
Ah, here she comes! Watame Shogun! Bow down!
強そう
She looks strong.
本当に思ってる？
Do you really think so?
思ってるよ！
I do!
弱そうだな...
She looks kind of weak...
弱そう、はははって乾いた笑いして
She looks weak, and that dry laughter, haha.
これ斬れるのかな？
Can this thing even cut?
いけますかね？
Can I do it?
ということで、いつもの通りまったりお喋りしていきましょう！
Anyway, let's have a relaxing chat as usual!
はーい！
Okay!
ということで、よーい、スタート！
Alright then, ready... set, go!
始まった！
It's started!
あ、始まりました。じゃあ我々とトークしてる間にね、海苔を食べれるかどうかでございますけど
Ah, it's begun. Now, let's see if you can eat the seaweed while we talk.
オッケー
Okay.
ちなみに、まあ、あの夏休みの話題がね、獅白のところで出てたんですけど、
By the way, the topic of summer vacation came up in Botan's stream earlier.
うん
Yeah.
夏休みといえば、バカタレでもし夏休みを過ごすなら、なんかしたいこととかありますか？
Speaking of summer vacation, if we were to spend it as Bakatare, is there anything you'd like to do?
したいこと？
Something I want to do?
したいこと...
Something I want to do...
なんだろうな〜
I wonder what it would be...
何がしたい、わためなら？
What would you like to do, Watame?
お泊まりで朝までゲームやりてぇ〜！
I want to have a sleepover and play games until morning!
やりてぇ〜！
I want to do that too!
やったわ、でも、前になんか...
We've done that before, but...
ホラゲとかしようぜ
Let's play a horror game or something.
ね、ホラゲ
Yeah, a horror game.
あ！わため、食べてる！今！
Ah! Watame, you're eating! Right now!
なに？
What?
今！わため！なんですか？
Right now! Watame! What was that?
食べた？
Did you eat it?
食べた...
I ate it...
はい、残念！白上が今早かったので、次はね、フレアが頑張ってやってください
Too bad! Fubuki was too quick for you. Flare, you try your best next time.
分かりました
Understood.
また、あわよくばお泊まりまたしたいですね
I'd really love to have another sleepover if possible.
したいね
I would too.
他に何、といえばなんだろう
What else... I wonder.
二人は何したい？
What do you two want to do?
え、なんだろうな。フレア何したい？
Hmm, I wonder. Flare, what do you want to do?
えー、なんだろうな〜
Hmm, what could it be...
でもなんかさ、ドライブとかしたいね、旅行とか。温泉とか行きたいね
You know, I'd like to go for a drive, or a trip. I'd love to go to a hot spring.
あ、温泉いいなー
Ah, a hot spring sounds nice.
ねー
Right?
ゴロゴロしたいな、みんなと
I just want to lounge around with everyone.
したいね
Me too.
あー、食べたー、二人とももっと喋ってー！
Ah, I ate it! You two, keep talking more!
なんかいまフブちゃんめっちゃ静かになった。
Wait, Fubuki-chan just went really quiet.
うそだー。聞き耳立てないでよー。
No way! Don't try to listen in!
にょ、でも自分も指摘できないのでねー。
Well, I can't really call her out either.
私だったらそうだなぁ。
If it were me, let's see...
ちょっと難しいけど、いつかみんなで海とかに行ってスイカ割りしたいねー。
It might be hard, but I'd like to go to the beach and do watermelon splitting with everyone.
あ、いいねーしたいねー！
Oh, that sounds nice! I want to do that!
いいねー。あとバーベキューとかね。いいよね、やっぱりね。
Nice. And a BBQ too. That would be great.
いいお肉の匂いとか嗅ぎたいしね。お野菜もね。
I want to smell good meat. And vegetables too.
お肉いっぱい食べたいな。おいしいなー。
I want to eat lots of meat. It's so tasty.
ふむふむ。思うんだけどもー。
I see, I see. I was thinking though...
他はなんだろう。夏といえば。
What else is there? Speaking of summer.
なんだろうねー。なんだろうなー。
I wonder... what else?
あ、花火とかもしたいね！
Oh, I want to do fireworks too!
あー、いいねー！花火もね！
Ah, that's great! Fireworks too!
ねー。お、フレア、フレア大丈夫かこれ。わための指摘できるか、ちゃんと。
Right. Hey, Flare, are you okay? Can you catch Watame out properly?
大丈夫かなー。なんか常にもぐもぐ言ってる気がするけど。
I wonder... I feel like she's always making munching sounds.
気がする。気のせいか。気のせいか。
I feel it too. Maybe it's just imagination?
いま食べてない。気のせいか。
I'm not eating right now. It's your imagination.
あー、気のせいかー。なるほど。気のせいかー。
Ah, just imagination. I see. Just imagination.
また夏といえば、ホロライブサマー、来年は、あるといいですねー。
Speaking of summer again, it would be nice if there's a Hololive Summer next year.
あねー。そういえば、二人の、ちょっと、お水着も、見たいぞー。
Right. Speaking of which, I want to see you two in swimsuits too.
ちょ、見て、これ！
Wait, look at this!
見て！
Look!
なに？なに？
What? What?
これ、わ、ばいんばいん、なうふでじましだー！
This... wow, it's bouncy! (Muffled speech while eating)
あらららら。
Oh my, oh my.
なうふでじまっだー！
(Muffled speech continued)
なうふでじまったなー。なうふだーよ。
She's totally muffled! It's 'naufu'.
残念だねー。ホロライブサマー。バロンバロンでいきたいです！
Too bad about Hololive Summer. I want to go all out with 'Baron Baron'!
バルンバルンで。水着ならわため、どんなのがいい。ビキニになるの？それともなんかワンピース型？
Barun Barun. Watame, what kind of swimsuit would you want? A bikini? Or maybe a one-piece?
ビキニ。ビキニ。
Bikini. Bikini.
どっちがいいの？ビキニなの？
Which one's better? A bikini?
ワンピースかなー。ワンピース型の可愛いやつ。
Maybe a one-piece. A cute one-piece type.
ビキニもいいねー。大人なビキニだね。
A bikini is nice too. A mature bikini.
ねー、ビキニ。まだ、何歳だったっけ、わためは。五歳だよ。
Yeah, bikini. Wait, how old was Watame again? I'm five years old.
五歳や。ちょっと、わからない大人のはね。
Five years old. You might not understand 'adult' things yet.
いいでしょう。ねー。
It's fine, right?
いいでしょうねー。フレアは、フレア似合いそうだな。でもエッチなフレアは、
I'm sure it would be. Flare, it would look good on you. But as for 'sexy' Flare...
私は逆に、着たくないんだよね、あんまり、エッチすぎるのは。
On the contrary, I don't really want to wear anything that's too sexy.
あ、じゃあ、可愛い系か。
Oh, so a cute style then?
可愛いのがいいね。フリルいっぱいがいいなー。いいねー。
I like cute things. Something with lots of frills. That would be nice.
あ、ということで、いま食べたよ！わため！
Wait, I saw it! You just ate, Watame!
本当に？食べて。嘘、一枚しかわからなかったかも。
Really? Did she eat? No way, I might have only noticed one piece.
なんだよー。
What's this?
えー、なんかさっき食べたかな、と思ったら、食べてなかったしねー。難しいな。
Eh? I thought she ate just now, but then she hadn't. This is hard.
おれ、難しかったね。三枚食べて、一枚目バレて。
That was tough. I ate three pieces, and only the first one was caught.
三枚食べたの！？
You ate three pieces!?
そう。二枚目は、ふーたんが、夏休みの話してるときに食べてー。
Yeah. The second one, I ate while Fu-tan was talking about summer vacation.
三枚目は、いま、ほっぺたに入ってるよ。
And the third one is in my cheek right now.
え、入ってるの？嘘、パリパリ音聞こえなかった。
Wait, it's in there? No way, I didn't hear a crunch.
ねー、ちょっと湿気てたよ。湿気てた。
Well, it was a bit soggy. It was soggy.
湿気てたら、それ音聞こえねえな、パリパリ。悔しいー！
If it's soggy, you won't hear that crunch. How frustrating!
イェーイ。悔しいけど、これは、わための勝ちだから。
Yay! It's frustrating, but this is Watame's win.
やったー！キーワード発表すっかー！お願いします！
Yay! Time to announce the keyword! Please go ahead!
あ、私がいっていいの？あ、いっていいですよ、いいよ、二人でね。
Oh, am I the one to say it? Yes, you can. Go ahead, both of you.
じゃあ、キーワードは、「ら」です！「ら」！
Alright, the keyword is... 'Ra'! 'Ra'!
「ら」です。ふーみママもいまね、ちょっと、あっちの、後ろから出してきてあげるよ。しょうがない。
It's 'Ra'. I'll bring Fumi-mama out from back there too. Can't be helped.
最後のキーワードもらおうか。解放しよう。はい。
Let's get the final keyword. Let's release her. Okay.
ということでじゃあ、ふーみママをまた、再召喚しますので。はい。はい、最後のキーワードをもらってください。
And with that, I'll be re-summoning Fumi-mama. Yes. Please receive the final keyword.
よかったー、いっぱい喋れて。ね。じゃあねー、わため。
I'm glad we got to talk a lot. Right. See you later, Watame.
よかった。お城に帰るよ、一緒に。わかった。じゃあ先に帰ってるから、わためも後で帰ってこいよ。
That's good. Let's go back to the castle together. Got it. I'll head back first, so you come back later too, Watame.
後で行くわー。行くわー。うーん、じゃあねー。ダメ、ありがとう。
I'll go later. I'll go! Mmm, see you then. No, thanks.
後で行くねー！ばいばーい！ばいばーい！
I'll be there later! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
お、ふーみママ帰ってくるかなー？ふーみママ！
Oh, is Fumi-mama coming back? Fumi-mama!
ただいまー。わため、大丈夫だった？
I'm back. Watame, were you okay?
大丈夫。大丈夫じゃなかった。大丈夫じゃなかった。何されて、大丈夫？
I'm okay. Actually, I wasn't. I wasn't okay. What happened, are you alright?
なんかいろんな、いろいろ、あれされました。
Well, all sorts of... all sorts of things were done to me.
いろいろされました。ちょっといろんな女の子たちに弄ばれました。
A lot of things happened. I was teased by a bunch of different girls.
いろんなことを、想像、ちょっと想像かき立てられて興奮しちゃう。
Imagining all those things... my imagination is running wild and it's getting me excited.
あ、でも無事でよかった。それでは、私からキーワードをお伝えしたいと思います。
Ah, but I'm glad you're safe. Now then, I'd like to give you the keyword from my side.
はい！お願いします！キーワードは、ドン！「ぶ」です！
Yes! Please! The keyword is... Bam! 'Bu'!
「ぶ」！？「ぶ」ってなんだ？「ぶ」？
'Bu'!? What's 'Bu'? 'Bu'?
それでは、キーワードが揃ったと思うので、私は帰ります。えー、ママ、おやすみー、ありがとう、お城でね。お城でね。
Well then, I think all the keywords are gathered now, so I'll be heading off. Eh? Mama, goodnight! Thanks, see you at the castle. At the castle.
二人で一緒に考えましょう。
Let's think about this together.
お、考える？
Oh, we're thinking?
これなんだと思う？
What do you think this is?
６かぁ...なんだろうな...
A '6'... I wonder what it is...
なんか...そら？
Maybe... Sora?
そらちゃん？
Sora-chan?
なんかいろいろ考えられるよね。
There are many possibilities.
ねー。
Yeah.
なんか「Ｉ」とかは、ローマ字で読んでみたらどうかな？
How about reading that 'I' as a Roman letter?
Ｉ...
I...
Ｉってなんて読むの？
How do you read 'I'?
ママ教えて！
Tell me, Mama!
「イ」かな？
Maybe 'i'?
イ。
'i'.
イって読むの？
You read it as 'i'?
なんだ？
What is it?
え、これ、漢字はなんて読むの？
Wait, how do you read this Kanji?
漢字は「ぶ」っていう...
The Kanji is read as 'bu'...
ぶ！
Bu!
お？
Oh?
...ライブ？
...Live?
ライブ？
Live?
え、６はなんて読むの？
Wait, how do you read the '6'?
６、なんて読むの？
How do you read '6'?
私が答えちゃっていいの、これ？
Is it okay if I just give the answer?
ダメダメダメダメ！
No, no, no, no!
なんて読むの？
How do you read it?
じゃあ、あとはわためちゃんで考えてみてくださーい。
Well then, please figure out the rest for yourself, Watame-chan.
えー！そんなぁ！
Ehh! No way!
またねー。
See ya.
ういママもありがとう！
Thanks, Uimi-mama!
バクダイさんもありがとう！
Thanks, Bakudai-san!
え、これ、もしかして...
Wait, could this be...
そ、そ...
So... so...
わためのソロライブ！？
Watame's solo live!?
ソロライブ！？
A solo live!?
え？
What?
本当に！？
Really!?
ホロライブ４期生の、角巻わためです。
I'm Tsunomaki Watame from Hololive's 4th generation.
2021年の、最初のわためダイレクトを動画にまとめましたので...
I've compiled the first 'Watame Direct' of 2021 into this video...
ご覧ください！
Please take a look!
Tsunomaki Watame 1st Live「わためぇ Night Fever!!」 in Zepp Tokyo
Tsunomaki Watame 1st Live 'Watame Night Fever!!' in Zepp Tokyo
Zepp Tokyo 2021.10.12 #わためソロライブ Supported By Bushiroad
Zepp Tokyo 2021.10.12 #WatameSoloLive Supported By Bushiroad
というわけで！角巻わため、ソロライブの開催が、決定しましたー！！
And so! It's been decided that Tsunomaki Watame will hold a solo live concert!!
イェーイ！！
Yay!!
今日の告知を手伝ってくれた、みんな、そしてホロライブのみんな、運営さん...
Everyone who helped with today's announcement, everyone in Hololive, the management...
今日応援してくれている、みんな...
Everyone who's supporting me today...
そして今この配信をね、させてくれてるスタッフの方、マネージャーさん...
And the staff and managers who are making this stream possible...
本当に、いろんな、いろんな人の力のおかげで...
Thanks to the help of so many different people...
読みます！
I'll read it!
公式正式タイトル、角巻わため 1st Live「わためぇ Night Fever!!」in Zepp Tokyo...
The official title: Tsunomaki Watame 1st Live 'Watame Night Fever!!' in Zepp Tokyo...
Supported By Bushiroad！！
Supported By Bushiroad!!
イェーイ！！
Yay!!
公式ハッシュタグは...
The official hashtag is...
シャープわためソロライブ、わためが平仮名で...
#WatameSoloLive, with 'Watame' in Hiragana...
ソロライブがカタカナです。
...and 'Solo Live' in Katakana.
当日いっぱいツイートしてください。
Please tweet a lot on that day.
そして！会場が！Zepp Tokyo！！
And! The venue is! Zepp Tokyo!!
イェーイ！！
Yay!!
Zepp Tokyo、今年でもう閉めちゃうみたいなんですけど...
It seems Zepp Tokyo is closing down later this year...
最初で最後ですね、ホロライブでZepp Tokyoに立つやつは。
So I'll be the first and last person from Hololive to stand on the Zepp Tokyo stage.
10月12日、火曜日。
October 12th, Tuesday.
開場、オープンが、17時。夕方の5時。
Doors open at 17:00. That's 5 PM.
そして配信、あ、配信...開演かな。スタートが、18時。
And the stream... wait, the performance start time is 18:00.
夕方の6時からです。
That's 6 PM.
んで、配信の方のオープンが、17時半、5時半。
And the online stream will open at 17:30, or 5:30 PM.
ちょっと会場とは30分後になるんですけど、17時30分。
That's 30 minutes after the venue doors open, at 17:30.
そして、配信の方スタートが18時、6時。これは、会場の方と配信の方両方同じになっとります。
And the stream starts at 18:00, or 6 PM. This is the same for both the venue and the stream.
...ます。
...forward to it.
会場チケットスケジュールが、
The venue ticket schedule is...
1次先行、抽選になっているんですけど、
...for the first-round advance lottery,
受付がなんと、8月19日(木)、今日の22時から、
and applications open at 10 PM today, Aug 19th (Thu),
8月29日(日)の23時59分まで受け付けております。
until August 29th (Sun) at 11:59 PM.
ちょっと抽選だからね、あんまり急がなくてもいいかなと思います。
Since it's a lottery, there's no need to rush too much.
一般発売が9月25日の土曜日、12時から開始です。
General sales start at 12 PM on Saturday, Sept 25th.
会場チケット代 ¥6,500
Venue Ticket: 6,500 yen
会場チケット代は、6,500円となっております。
Venue tickets will be 6,500 yen.
会場チケットや現地での注意事項等詳細は、ホームページがあるんで、特設ホームページを...
For details and venue precautions, please check the special website...
あ噛んでる！特設ホームページをチェックしてください。
I stumbled! Please check the special website.
ちょっとご時世的にね、どうなるかまだ分かんないんですけど、現地でね、できればやりたいなと思っております。
With the current situation, things are uncertain, but I'd love to do it in person.
そして配信の方でもある、配信プラットフォームのSPWNでも配信をさせていただきます。
The event will also be streamed on the SPWN platform.
8月19日、22時、10時から、この後ですね、この後10時から、
From 10 PM today, August 19th...
11月12日、23時59分まで販売、
...tickets are on sale until Nov 12th, 11:59 PM.
イベント開催後の1ヶ月後までアーカイブ視聴可能です。11月12日まで見れます。
The archive will be available for one month after the event, until Nov 12th.
アーカイブは何度でも視聴可能です。
You can watch the archive as many times as you like.
このSPWNさんの配信チケット代の方が5,000円となっております。
The SPWN streaming ticket is 5,000 yen.
そしてなんと、デジタルフラスタというものが送れるんですけど、
And surprisingly, you can also send Digital Flustas!
デジタルフラスタ受付が、2021年8月19日木曜日この後10時から、
Applications open at 10 PM today, August 19th (Thu),
2021年9月19日日曜日23時59分まで。
until September 19th (Sun), 11:59 PM.
会場から開演までの舞台などでデジタルフラスタが掲載されます。
They will be displayed from doors open until the performance starts.
詳しくはSPWNのページをチェックしてください。
Please check the SPWN page for more details.
あとなんと！なんと！グッズも出ます！
And... and... there's also merchandise!
イェーイ！ライブグッズ！
Yay! Live goods!
こちらが応援セットとなっておりまして、
This is the "Support Set."
ライブTシャツとタオルとペンライトとわための面白パリピサングラスですね。
It has a T-shirt, towel, penlight, and my funny Paripi sunglasses.
これまるっとセットで13,000円となっております。
The whole set is 13,000 yen.
このセットをご購入いただきますと、角巻わため複製メッセージ入りミニ色紙キーホルダーをプレゼントします！
Buy the set and get a mini shikishi keychain with my printed message!
めっちゃいい感じなので、よかったらセットご購入してみてください。これはライブ前に届くようになっております。
It's really nice, so please check it out. These will arrive before the live.
あとは、バラ売りもさせていただきます。
Items will also be sold individually.
先行発送グッズ1、ライブTシャツ 4,000円、タオル 2,500円。
Advance shipment 1: T-shirt for 4,000 yen, towel for 2,500 yen.
そして、ペンライト。
And the penlight...
3,500円です。あとわための面白パリピサングラス、ぜひお揃っちしましょう。これが3,000円となっております。
...is 3,500 yen. And the sunglasses are 3,000 yen. Let's match!
いや付けてほしいなー、ぜひ。これもライブの前に届くようになってるので。
I really want you to wear them! These will also arrive before the live.
よかったらお手にとって頂けると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you picked them up.
あとは後日発送のグッズもあります。
There are also items for post-event shipment.
キービジュアルB2タペストリー 3,000円。そしてわためいとアイマスク。
The key visual B2 tapestry for 3,000 yen and Wata-mate eye mask.
わためいとがグッズになりましたー！2,000円。
Wata-mate has become merch! It's 2,000 yen.
あとはセトリキーホルダー。わためがライブ当日歌ったセトリがキーホルダーになって、思い出としてみんなの元に残ります。
And the setlist keychain. The setlist from the day will be kept as a memory.
よかったら思い出にいかがでしょうか。ぜひ買っていただきたいなと思います。
How about one for the memories? I'd love for you to get one.
グッズ受注期間が8月19日この後10時から9月5日23時59分まで。
Orders open at 10 PM today until Sept 5th, 11:59 PM.
日本のユーザーさんはもちろん、海外のわためいと、オーバーシーもグッズ申し込みができます！
Orders are open to fans in Japan and overseas Wata-mates too!
オーバーシーのみんなは、GeekJackをチェックしてください。
Overseas fans, please check GeekJack.
そして、ちょっとサングラス見たいよね。
And you want to see the sunglasses, right?
見せるよ、ちょっと写真撮ってあるから。
I'll show you. I took some photos.
見て見て！いや意外といいよね、これ。
Look, look! They're actually pretty good, right?
これをね、ちょっと付けてもらったから、それもね、見ていきましょうかね。
I had someone try them on, so let's take a look.
なんとなんと！ベストガール！
Wow, wow! Best girl!
やっほー、やっほー、社長が、見つけてくれました。
Ya-hoo! Ya-hoo! The CEO, he found them.
かわいい〜！
So cute!
みんなもぜひわためとやごー社長と谷郷社長とお揃いしましょう！
Everyone, please get the same pair as Watame, YAGOO-shacho, and Tanigo-shacho!
そしてこのあとプレミア公開、10時からわための
And after this, at 10 PM, the premiere of my
オリジナルソング『mayday, mayday』が投稿されるので...
original song 'mayday, mayday' will be posted...
10時からもぜひ見てください！動画見てください！
So please watch it at 10 PM! Please watch the video!
mayday, mayday 作詞・作曲 Junky 配信開始日 2021/8/20 0:00〜
mayday, mayday Lyrics/Composition: Junky. Distribution starts 2021/8/20 at 0:00.
そのあと、今日の24時、0時、8月20日0時、
After that, today at 24:00, 0:00, Aug 20th at 0:00,
今日の24時に『mayday, mayday』がなんと...
today at 24:00, 'mayday, mayday' will...
iTunesさんとかで買えます！
be available on iTunes and other platforms!
よかったら、いっぱい聞いてください、買ってください、お願いします！
If you like, please listen to it a lot, please buy it, please!
あとは24時から、メン限でお話をしたいなと思っているので、
Also, from 24:00, I'm thinking of doing a member-only talk stream,
よかったら、メンバーに入ってくださっている方はお話しましょう！
so if you're a member, let's talk!
いや〜情報盛りだくさんだったけど、わかったかな？日付とかいっぱい言ったけど、大丈夫だったかな？
Wow, that was a lot of information, did you get it all? I said a lot of dates, was it okay?
ちょっとね、情報、これからも更新いろいろされるかな、と思うので、
The information might be updated in the future,
概要欄にもいっぱい書いてあると思うので、チェックしてみてください。
and there's a lot written in the description, so please check it out.
あと特設サイトがね、めっちゃいい感じなので、よかったら見てね！
Also, the special website looks really great, so please check it out if you like!
じゃあ最後はわためのあの曲で締めたいと思います！
Well, let's wrap things up with that song of mine!
『愛昧ショコラーテ』！
Aimai Chocolate!
愛昧ショコラーテ 作詞/作曲 Junky
Aimai Chocolate Lyrics/Composition: Junky
あー待てやっちゃった
Ah, wait, I did it
隠してたわけじゃないの
It's not that I was hiding it
きっとただ言ってないだけ
I probably just didn't say it
だって恥ずかしいんだもん
Because I'm embarrassed
みんなー！最高潮に盛り上がっていきましょー！
Everyone! Let's get pumped up to the max!
ライブの予行練習だと思って楽しんでいってください！
Think of this as a rehearsal for the live concert and enjoy!
意外と寂しん坊
Unexpectedly lonely
意外と甘えん坊
Unexpectedly spoiled
意外と慌てん坊
Unexpectedly klutzy
意外と照れ屋
Unexpectedly shy
丸い羊雲
Round sheep-clouds
飛び出したカップケーキ
Popped out cupcake
3回目コンディショナー
Third conditioner
余るパズル
Leftover puzzle
ふわふわ浮かぶ夢見心地
Fluffy floating dream-like feeling
ひとつひとつ数えておやすみなさい
Counting them one by one, good night
密かに芽生えたこの気持ち
This feeling that secretly sprouted
まっすぐ見つめないで
Don't look straight at me
なんだっけ
What was it?
言葉にしちゃときっとそうじゃない
If I put it into words, it's surely not like that
照れちゃうだけじゃなくちゃ、じゃな、じゃうじゃない
It's not just about being shy, it's, it's not
ホントのホントは隠したいんじゃないの、もうそうじゃないのにな
Truth is, I don't want to hide it, even though it's not like that anymore
曖昧なんじゃない
It's not ambiguous
この気持ちは間違いじゃない
This feeling isn't a mistake
指切りげんまん
Pinky swear
かなりドジっ子で
Quite a klutz
優柔不断でも
Even if I'm indecisive
絶対に毎日会いに来てくれるよな！
You'll definitely come to see me every day, right?!
本来臆病で
Inherently timid
案外な気持
Unexpected feeling
全然変わらずに
Without changing at all
辛い日ばかり
Only bitter days
当たり前のようにギュッてしちゃ
If I hug you like it's natural
君がいないとガッカリしちゃうわ
I'll be disappointed if you're not here
ホントのホントにしょんぼりしちゃうわ
I'll truly, truly be dejected
会いたくなっちゃうな
I'll start wanting to see you
後悔ばっかじゃ
If it's just regrets
この心も勇気出しちゃえ
Let this heart find some courage too
この指止まれ
Pinky swear
歌うことが大好きな、一人の、一匹の羊が、
A single sheep who loves singing,
こんなにたくさんの羊に囲まれて...
surrounded by so many sheep...
そして大きな大きな夢ができて、
And now, I have a big, big dream, and I believe
今回その夢に向かう第一歩だと思っています。
this is the first step toward that dream.
よかったらみんな、一緒に...
If you like, everyone, let's...
…その第一歩 踏み出してください！
…please take that first step!
見に来てね！
Please come and see me!
弱いところ気づかれちゃったり
Having my weak spots noticed
寂しさごと包まれちゃったり
Having even my loneliness embraced
いつまでも笑い合ったり
Laughing together forever
たまにはムッと喧嘩をしたり
And sometimes getting into grumbly fights
ずっとずっとそばにいてほしい
I want you to be by my side forever and ever
約束だぞ！
It's a promise!
言っちゃった もしかしたら運命かも
I said it... Maybe it's destiny
赤い糸が見えちゃうかも
Maybe I'll see the red thread of fate
ホントのホントはバレてるのかも
Maybe you've already found out the real, real truth
目合わせらんないかも
Maybe I can't even look you in the eyes
曖昧なんてない
There's nothing ambiguous about it
たくさん私を見てて
Keep your eyes on me
指切りった！
Pinky promise made!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
待ってるよー！
I'll be waiting!
Tsunomaki Watame 1st Live: わためぇ Night Fever!! in Zepp Tokyo 2021.10.12 Tue.
Tsunomaki Watame 1st Live: Watame Night Fever!! in Zepp Tokyo (2021.10.12 Tue.)
重大告知 …わため呼び出し?!
Major Announcement: Watame Summoned?!